recent HS research shows that 97% of web
pages get zero organic search traffic
from Google so what does the top 3% do
differently well that's what you're
going to learn right now I'll show you a
proven four pillar SEO blueprint to help
you rank number one in Google for
example this page grew by
214% in only 30 days using this
blueprint then we use it again to grow
this website's organic traffic by 300%
so if you're new here I'm gotch and for
over a decade I've LED hundreds of
successful SEO campaigns in the most
competitive Industries such as legal
health and SAS I'm also the founder of
the number one SEO training program
gotch SEO Academy author of The SEO
entrepreneur and co-founder of
rankability so let's begin with pillar
number one exploit your SEO competitors
so search your keyword on Google and
then open up the top five competitors
next create a Google sheet because we'll
identify the competitor's strengths and
weaknesses the first step is to study
their onpage SEO so while on the
competitor's page click on the detailed
Chrome extension copy the title and meta
description and add it to the Google
sheet then click on the headings tab
copy the H1 text and add it to the
Google sheet as well then go to the page
copy the first official paragraph and
add it to the Google sheet the last step
is to run the keyword through rank
abilties content Optimizer click on the
competitors tab copy the rankability
score and add it to the sheet the
rankability score simply measures a
Page's relevance and topic coverage
compared to the top competitors for that
keyword then just repeat this process
for the rest of the top five competitors
and do it for your Target URL if you
have one and if you're not ranking in
the top 100 you can still collect your
rankability score by entering your URL
on the competitor's Tab and once you
have all the data it's time to analyze
let's start with the URL column in this
example only one competitor uses the
best URL structure which includes the
whole keyword phrase the other four
competitors are missing Chicago in the
structure imagine if we remove the root
domain and you had to figure out what
the page was about without looking at
the content that's what you're forcing
Google to try to figure out and Google
is good at understanding relevance but
it's far from perfect you need to treat
the algorithms like a one-year-old spoon
feed at the inputs it needs to fully
understand your Page's content and it
begins with the URL next look at the
title tag notice that the top three
compe s have the exact match phrase in
the title this is perfect number four
and number five have the keywords mixed
in but it doesn't explicitly State the
exact match keyword phrase and our
example page doesn't include lawyer or
Chicago in the title they could climb at
least 25 spots in the rankings by simply
changing their title tag and this isn't
Theory Google's leaked documents have a
feature called title match score which
measures how well the title matches the
keyword now moving on on to the metad
description which is a tiny Factor but
there are a few things to note here
first Simply Having a metad description
and including the primary phrase might
be a tiny ranking Factor secondly I
recommend not including your phone
number in the title or The Meta
description now this might seem
counterintuitive because the goal is to
drive leads but from an SEO perspective
you want Searchers to actually click
through on your result because organic
CTR is a proven ranking Factor remember
that your title and metad descript deson
aren't visible to users on your website
but appear in Google search results the
H1 tag on the other hand is what users
can see and it's essential for SEO and
the top three competitors in this
example are doing it correctly but the
others are not next you should include
the primary keyword phrase in the first
paragraph once again the top ranking
result is doing this incredibly well and
last but definitely not least you need
to measure topic coverage for your page
and the top two competitors have the
most relevant and comprehensive Pages
for this target keyword I'll cover how
to do this later in the video so at this
point we haven't even studied the pages
themselves but it's already clear how to
win by simply exploiting the competitors
on page SEO weaknesses but now that we
have the basics covered it's time to
identify our angles of differentiation I
analyzed the top 10 for this keyword and
found multiple angles for winning number
one match the intent 100% perfectly if
someone is searching for motorcycle
accident attorney they or someone they
know has likely been in an accident that
means that the goal of this page is to
get the Searcher to know like and Trust
the lawyer and that's accomplished by
creating bottom of the funnel or
conversion focused content like
testimonials case studies unique selling
propositions and any other information
that helps the prospect make an educated
decision now what shouldn't be on this
page is safety tips for bikers this type
of content is fine for a blog post but
it doesn't match the intent of the
keyword phrase in other words that type
of content doesn't help this person get
closer to their goal of hiring a
competent lawyer and getting a sizable
settlement number two crush the
competition with better content design
so having words just to have words
doesn't help SEO or conversion rate
optimization instead you should
scrutinize every page Element Section
and the copyrighting ask one simple
question does this help the prospect get
closer to becoming a lead I'll show you
how to design your content using real
life examples later in the video and now
moving on to number three install
engagement triggers so it's now proven
that Google uses user signals as one
variable to determine rankings and there
are ways to ethically increase
engagement on your page while helping
users achieve their goals in this
example we could add extremely well
produced video that gets users to click
watch and increase their dwell time on
the page we could also create and embed
a micro calculator specifically for
motorcycle accidents on this page for
example how much is your motorcycle
accident case worth a simple calculator
embedded on this page will massively
increase the volume of user interaction
on the page itself so at this point we
know how to differentiate from our
competitors now it's time for pillar
number two which is feed the machine so
NLP or natural language processing is
the technology used by Google Amazon
Facebook and other Tech Giants to under
understand human language and we can use
it in the context of SEO to create
insanely relevant pages that Google's
algorithms love here's how it works
simply enter a keyword into rankability
and the tool scrapes the content from
the top competitors and uses NLP to
extract topics from that content as a
result the NLP recommendations are
simply what your top competitors cover
in their pages and you want to cover the
same topics but with better quality
depth and different iation but the first
step is to build an effective outline so
go back into rankability copy the NLP
keywords open chat GPT and use the
following prompt and now we'll take this
outline to the next level copy the law
firm's about page and feed that back
into chat gbt to revise the outline then
just paste the outline back in
rankability now add a human touch to the
outline and once you're confident it's
time for pillar number three which is
create an addictive page and that begins
with copyrighting but there's a dilemma
should you use AI or human to write this
content well I analyzed the top five
results for Chicago Motorcycle accent
lawyer and three of five use human
written content including the number one
result who you should try to Dethrone so
in this case I would go with human
written content so go back to
rankability Click Share enable the
shared link copy it and open it up this
link will allow the copywriter to see
the content brief and they'll be able to
write the content within the content
Optimizer without even needing an
account advise your copywriter to hit
the low end of the word count Target as
this will force them to create lean and
compelling copy they should also aim for
the optimal rankability score ensuring
your page is more relevant than the top
competitors and most importantly tell
your copywriter not to worry about how
often they mention a specific topic
instead focus on covering each topic
entirely now that may take a sentence or
an entire paragraph but focus on topic
coverage not keyword stuffing so once
the copy is ready and fully optimized
it's time to design your content an
effective lead generation page should
really be designed like a sales page and
that means you need to focus on the core
elements of persuasion such as emotion
logic and fear but before we geek out
about persuasive copyrighting you need
to brainstorm the offer for this page
and no free consultation is not an offer
you need to give a Searcher a reason to
contact you right now pretend that this
is the only opportunity you get to
capture this lead what kind of offer
would you give them well the good news
is you don't have to be David ogy to
formulate a strong offer just open chat
gbt and use the following prompt in
seconds you'll have a solid offer to
build upon and once you're satisfied
it's time to mock up the page now don't
reinvent the wheel that's why I
recommend keeping a swipe file of design
elements and marketing techniques you
like use the following techniques to
build an SEO driven commercial page that
actually converts number one obsess
about your above the fold section you've
probably heard that 80% of people only
read headlines and it's true you can get
the evidence Yourself by installing user
tracking software like Mouse flow and in
about a week you'll realize that most
people don't scroll and that means that
you're above the fold section is
critical to success this lawyer keeps it
insanely simple and makes the cta's the
star of the show and this Law Firm uses
a strong headline CTA and social proof
finally my favorite showcases a
beautiful design a form above the fold
and quick unique selling propositions
number two pour on the social proof 97%
of consumers look at reviews before
buying a product and testimonials can
increase conversions by 34% that's why
social proof in the form of written
testimonials client results and video
testimonials are an integral part of any
effective commercial page number three
use logic so Zig Ziggler said people buy
on emotion and justify with logic and
that's why 80% of the elements on your
page should appeal to emotion however a
segment of buyers is heavily influenced
by Logic and that's why you should
include sections like this one that
outline the legal process that they're
about to go through or this one that
hits on the firm's unique selling
propositions all right so now moving on
to pillar number four Force Google to
trust your website Google recently said
that its ranking systems aim to
understand if a section of a site is
independent or starkly different from
the main content of the site that means
that Google's algorithms will prefer a
website that stays within its circle of
competence in the case of our keyword we
must create many supporting assets to
train the algorithm to believe we're
experts in this field start by looking
at the people also ask section on Google
when you search your primary keyword
based on results we can create
supporting assets like how much are most
motorcycle accs and settlements in
Chicago why do Chicago insurance
companies total motorcycles with little
damage and what are the odds of having a
motorcycle accident in Chicago so within
just a few minutes you'll have tons of
ideas to build support around your main
page but just make sure that you
internally link back out to your
commercial page from all these
informational assets but most
importantly Crosslink these
informational assets together to form a
strong cluster next open semrush enter
your domain go to backlink analytics and
click on indexed page Pages then you'll
see the most powerful pages on your
website from a backlink perspective look
for opportunities to add internal links
on these pages to your SEO driven
commercial page and after that it's time
to create linkable content so the truth
is that not all content is linkable for
example a page about what time is it in
Chicago won't be effective for link
building however a page like 75 Chicago
motor cycle accident statistics for 2025
is much more likely to work for link
building purposes so here are a couple
of techniques you can use to create more
linkable content reverse engineer your
competitors so enter your competitor's
domain in semrush click on backlink
analytics and go to index Pages now
you'll see all the pages that have
attracted the most backlinks then just
repeat this process for your domain as
well what's work to attract back links
to your website then just do more of
what works the next technique is to use
chat gbt so just use the following
prompt to generate endless link bait
ideas with chat gbt just pick one idea
from the syntax and you'll have ideas to
work on within a few seconds and then
once you've created a few linkable
assets it's time to launch a link
building campaign watch the next video
to learn nine proven link building
strategies we used to grow a client's
organic search traffic by 300%